<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-12-26T09:24:59+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Skanda Shastry</title><subtitle>A blog about technology and stuff related</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Bits vs Atom!!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Bits-vs-atom/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bits vs Atom!!" /><published>2018-10-10T22:44:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-10-10T22:44:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Bits-vs-atom</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Bits-vs-atom/">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Our nuclear bases still use CD/floppy disk. 
Our new fighter can’t even fly in the rain.
Instead of going to mars, we have invaded the Middle East.
We wanted flying cars, we got 140 characters. 
 — Peter Thiel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Energy consumption &amp;amp; speed of vehicle still stagnant. Automobiles still travel 80–100mph on our highways. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Boeing 747 first flew in 1969, yet it still is the main jet carrying people across Pacific oceans. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Until Motorola &amp;amp; Nokia come up with mobile phone AT &amp;amp; T never do any innovation in its telephone &amp;amp; telegraph design. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*Ae6ZMqanDngaBOr18KsxxQ.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Markdowm Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;figcaption class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Data is the new Oil&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Above examples reflect, where we moving in the field of innovation &amp;amp; research. All the innovation in 20th mostly on Atoms &amp;amp; 21st century with Bits. Most of the companies in the world majorly categorized either bits or atoms companies &amp;amp; its part of one of the below 5 business models.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Bits:&lt;/b&gt; Company which builds on bits &amp;amp; bytes (0s &amp;amp; 1s) as a fundamental building block. most of the Internet/Software company survive with this principle. Innovation in this area is consistently accelerating in this area. there are too many bits companies right now (WhatsApp, Google, Facebook, Twitter) 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; 
&lt;b&gt;Atoms:&lt;/b&gt; The smallest unit of matter. &amp;amp; The company which builds purely based on substances aka company having physical visible products. Innovation in this area is consistently slow down in this area. (Ford, Coca-Cola, YKK, Luxottica, GE)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt; Combined Bit &amp;amp; Atom : &lt;/b&gt;
However, the above two sectors are not mutually exclusive. There is a 3rd group where the most successful companies are coming up with products and services that really do combine the best of both worlds i.e. bits and atoms.
The most interesting start-ups seem to sit at the intersection of the two — they use bits to manipulate atoms. (Apple, Amazon, Uber) control over both bit (software) &amp;amp; atom (Hardware) market.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;b&gt; Converting Atoms to Bits : &lt;/b&gt; 
The new internet age was all about the overwhelming superiority of customer experience &amp;amp; transforming the atoms to bits across the information superhighway.
* Conversion of the Books to kindle, &lt;br /&gt;
 * Plastic CD/DVD, walkmans to iTunes, &lt;br /&gt;
 * Money to PayPal/VISA,  &lt;br /&gt;
 * Blockbuster to Netflix, &lt;br /&gt;
 * Camera roll to Digital Image, &lt;br /&gt;
 * Print media (Newspaper) to FB/Twitter, &lt;br /&gt;
 * College classes to Online classes (Udacity/Coursera)
 &amp;amp; many more atom contents converts into bit version, &amp;amp; become fabulously wealthy. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;b&gt; Converting bits to atom: &lt;/b&gt;
 There are hardly very few companies which transform the bits into atoms(Microprocessor, Biotech, Robotics, 3DPriniting ) In this model involves the highest Regulatory norms &amp;amp; Cost of conversion is high. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;b&gt;Here is the Complete story!!! 👇 👇  &lt;/b&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the full story of &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@skanda_shastry/bits-vs-atom-b23b16ed52f3&quot;&gt;bits vs Atom&lt;/a&gt;
—&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>skanda shastry</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Singularity" /><category term="Atom bits" /><category term="Transformation" /><summary type="html">Our nuclear bases still use CD/floppy disk. Our new fighter can’t even fly in the rain. Instead of going to mars, we have invaded the Middle East. We wanted flying cars, we got 140 characters.  — Peter Thiel</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/markdown.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How the Design Thinking Re-Imagined Billions of Life in India!!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Human-center-Design/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How the Design Thinking Re-Imagined Billions of Life in India!!" /><published>2017-06-10T22:44:00+05:30</published><updated>2017-06-10T22:44:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Human-center-Design</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Human-center-Design/">&lt;p&gt;In today’s digital transformation age,
The slogan ‘innovate or perish’ stands true to its words. As brands can only survive in the market if they are constantly innovating and offering something new on the platter with time. Ultimately, It’s the innovation that helps businesses differentiate their products and services from competition, deliver greater value to customers, and build brands. In order to survive in this battle, Design thinking is one of the best solutions&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kept “thinking outside the box” on this core principle new way to solve the wicked problems &amp;amp; Its a powerful tool to tackle the unknown.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*pMk3h0dIYMb_I1iJCjriPQ.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Markdowm Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Design vs Expeirence&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s Changed? &lt;br /&gt;
The Internet has changed absolutely everything,like other disruption affect the print media very badly from this way of consuming the news &amp;amp; Consumer behaviour around the world is changing dramatically.
&lt;br /&gt;
What is a better product design? &lt;br /&gt;
From above 3 set of Images, Starting from the conventional way of getting the news with comprehensive details,full of scrolling grids, videos and text (CNN BBC NBC, TOI) which include both relevant &amp;amp; irrelevant news.
Moved to the customised, hand curated, short, crisp and relevant news within 60 words.(In short, Flipboard)
Finally, we are in the age where, news feed based on your behavioural data &amp;amp; digital demography via AI, deep learning &amp;amp; chat bot (Quartz,Toutiao)
From the above example, there is a paradigm shift in the news consumption &amp;amp; also in the Product Design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Here are the few example about Human center design !!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the full story of &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@skanda_shastry/design-thinking-re-imagined-billions-of-life-in-india-e1e9cccaf0aa&quot;&gt;HumanCenter Design&lt;/a&gt;
—&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>skanda shastry</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Design Thinking" /><category term="Product Design" /><summary type="html">In today’s digital transformation age, The slogan ‘innovate or perish’ stands true to its words. As brands can only survive in the market if they are constantly innovating and offering something new on the platter with time. Ultimately, It’s the innovation that helps businesses differentiate their products and services from competition, deliver greater value to customers, and build brands. In order to survive in this battle, Design thinking is one of the best solutions</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/markdown.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Unlocking the Trillion Dollar Opportunity!!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/unlocking-trillion-dollar-Opportunity/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Unlocking the Trillion Dollar Opportunity!!" /><published>2017-04-22T22:44:00+05:30</published><updated>2017-04-22T22:44:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/unlocking-trillion-dollar-Opportunity</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/unlocking-trillion-dollar-Opportunity/">&lt;p&gt;In 1998, Kodak sold 85% of photo film worldwide.Next few years Digital Camara slowly overlap the photo film.
&lt;br /&gt;
In 2003, Iconic 1100 phone sold more than 500 million units by Nokia in an year. Which is highest selling phone till now.
&lt;br /&gt;
In 2010, Blockbuster one of the most recognizable brand in the video rental space having around 9,000 stores &amp;amp; more than 60,000 employees. The company filed for bankruptcy protection.
&lt;br /&gt;
In 2015, All the telecom operator in world together send 20B messages, which is less than 30B message send by the WhatsApp in a day.
&lt;br /&gt;
All the above well-known &amp;amp; monopoly companies are bankrupt &amp;amp; certainly there business model disappears!!
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
“People think the CEO/directors of those companies must have been dumb not to see what was happening, but they were not dumb, they were very, very talented people, but they still missed the transition and made assumptions that were shown to be pretty poor in hindsight, but seemed fine at the time”. This highlights the importance of having someone in the organisation asking, constantly, what are our competitors doing to disrupt our business and our business model.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We stand on the brink of a technological revolution that will fundamentally alter the way we live, work, and relate to one another. In its scale, scope, and complexity, this transformation will be unlike anything humankind has experienced before.This exponential growth transformed our life tremendously, in just a few years.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1600/1*xvRjMIkNO4P06ehEARx6nw.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Markdowm Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Here are the few areas where disruption happened &amp;amp; it will alter the way of people life!!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the full story of [Digital Disruption] (https://medium.com/@skanda_shastry/unlocking-the-trillion-dollar-opportunity-20ba4c9a89a4)
—&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>skanda shastry</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Innovation" /><category term="Digital Disruption" /><category term="Business model" /><summary type="html">In 1998, Kodak sold 85% of photo film worldwide.Next few years Digital Camara slowly overlap the photo film. In 2003, Iconic 1100 phone sold more than 500 million units by Nokia in an year. Which is highest selling phone till now. In 2010, Blockbuster one of the most recognizable brand in the video rental space having around 9,000 stores &amp;amp; more than 60,000 employees. The company filed for bankruptcy protection. In 2015, All the telecom operator in world together send 20B messages, which is less than 30B message send by the WhatsApp in a day. All the above well-known &amp;amp; monopoly companies are bankrupt &amp;amp; certainly there business model disappears!! “People think the CEO/directors of those companies must have been dumb not to see what was happening, but they were not dumb, they were very, very talented people, but they still missed the transition and made assumptions that were shown to be pretty poor in hindsight, but seemed fine at the time”. This highlights the importance of having someone in the organisation asking, constantly, what are our competitors doing to disrupt our business and our business model. We stand on the brink of a technological revolution that will fundamentally alter the way we live, work, and relate to one another. In its scale, scope, and complexity, this transformation will be unlike anything humankind has experienced before.This exponential growth transformed our life tremendously, in just a few years.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/markdown.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">:ramen: Indigo, minimalist jekyll theme</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/indigo-jekyll-theme/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title=":ramen: Indigo, minimalist jekyll theme" /><published>2016-01-23T22:10:00+05:30</published><updated>2016-01-23T22:10:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/indigo-jekyll-theme</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/indigo-jekyll-theme/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/sergiokopplin/indigo/gh-pages/assets/screen-shot.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Example of project - Indigo Minimalist Jekyll Template - &lt;a href=&quot;http://sergiokopplin.github.io/indigo/&quot;&gt;Demo&lt;/a&gt;. This is a simple and minimalist template for Jekyll for those who likes to eat noodles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What has inside?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gulp&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;BrowserSync&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stylus&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SVG&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Travis&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No JS&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/speed/pagespeed/insights/?url=http%3A%2F%2Fsergiokopplin.github.io%2Findigo%2F&quot;&gt;98/100&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://sergiokopplin.github.io/indigo/&quot;&gt;Check it out&lt;/a&gt; here.
If you need some help, just &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/sergiokopplin/indigo/issues&quot;&gt;tell me&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>johndoe</name></author><category term="project" /><category term="jekyll" /><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://koppl.in/indigo/assets/images/jekyll-logo-light-solid.png" /></entry></feed>